Jason Lindsey

Student of Computer Science & Engineering | Database Administrator | System Administrator | Aviation Quality Control | Veteran

Phone: 330-949-9414 Address: Canton, OH 44708

Website: www.linkedin.com/in/jason-r-

lindsey

Email: jlinanalyst@gmail.com

A retired military veteran who is extremely enthusiastic and self-motivated. 4+ years in database, network, and system administration. Strong knowledge of the aviation industry. 15 years experience in leadership and training individuals. Proven to accomplish tasks as an individual or part of a team. Developed a passion for programming languages and pursuing a degree in Computer Science & Engineering to start a challenging new career in software development.

https://jlin2381.github.io/

HONORS

President's List

Stark State

Spring 2022 - Fall 2022 - Spring 2023

SKILLS

Database Administrator

• Served as an administrator of a database for the National Guard. The database included 7 aircraft, countless part numbers & serial numbers, maintenance accomplished, and several hundred personnel.

Google Analytics Certificate

• Completed the Coursera Google Data Analytics course. The course gives an understanding of the processes used by a junior or associate data analyst. Acquired skills such as data cleaning, data analysis, and data visualization. Learned how to use spreadsheets, SQL, R programming, and Tableau.

System Administrator

 Maintained 27 laptops for the National Guard on a network used to document maintenance actions accomplished, personnel accomplishing maintenance, parts replaced, and serial numbers replaced. This also included cloning hard drives, running security updates, installing software, and diagnosing and fixing issues, on laptops with government security protocols.

Leadership

• Led small and large numbers of military personnel in various situations such as maintaining aircraft, managing flight time of personnel and aircraft, and the monthly training required for mechanics.

Programming Language

• Experience programming in C++, Visual Basic, Visual Basic .NET (VB.NET), Python, and Java.

Web Development

Experience in web development using Hypertext Markup Language, PHP, and Cascading Style Sheets.

Other Skills

- Github
- PhpStorm
- DB2
- Wordpress
- Elementor
- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft Powerpoint
- Research

Google Data Analytics Certificate

Jan 2022

Coursera

EXPERIENCE

H-P Products

January 2023 - Present

Web Developer - Intern

- •Create web pages that track all facets of the manufacturing world. Including but not limited to the manufacturing of parts through all processes, products being sold, and employees' attendance.
- •Query and manipulate data from tables In IBM DB2 database to provide data in web format.
- •Troubleshoot web and data query issues.

Stark State College

Jan 2022 to Present

Student

Flexjet Mar 2018 to Jul 2020

Quality Assurance Analyst

- Conducted quality audits and surveillance on the work performed during routine and non-routine maintenance events including work order content, aircraft maintenance records, yellow tags, 8130-3's, 337's, Supplemental Type Certificates, maintenance deferrals, weight & balance changes, Airworthiness Directives, and Service Bulletins to the extent necessary to ensure the aircraft is airworthy and in compliance with the regulations set forth by the FAA and company manuals.
- Ensured that RII requirements were met.
- Performed quality audits and surveillance of the computerized maintenance tracking program to ensure data entry updates have been performed accurately
- Ensured all FO-501's, yellow tags, 8130-3's, and other aircraft records are entered into the electronic log books (Filenet).
- Reviewed all special flight permits for accuracy and completeness
- Performed internal audits to ensure that company programs, systems, processes, and procedures were effective.
- Performed external audits to ensure the approved vendor maintenance network complied with the company standards and applicable regulations.
- Updated the computerized maintenance tracking program profile for newly inducted aircraft.
- Performed CFR 135 conformity inspections and ensured the aircraft met the required standards for placement onto the air carrier certificate.
- Performed quality audits on aircraft templates to ensure tasks were tracking in accordance with the inspection programs and aircraft maintenance manual requirements.
- Ensured that any aircraft that no longer met RVSM standards were properly tracked and reported to Operations until it again met RVSM standards.
- Ensured that all weight and balance amendments and aircraft weighing were performed accurately, recorded on appropriate company forms and routed to both the aircraft and aircraft records for permanent filing.

Ohio National Guard Oct 2014 to Mar 2018

Quality Assurance

- Established, developed, and implemented Facility Quality Assurance and Reliability programs.
- Served as the Quality Assurance Representative for the facility.
- Consulted Maintenance supervisors, Maintenance Test Pilots, and Facility Commander on technical procedures using technical manuals and directives.
- Monitored acceptance and transfer inspections, modifications, & time-limited components.
- Maintained Facility Maintenance Master Library.

- Created a complete digital Master Library using Excel using the Familiarization Charts as a format.
- Added the program to the network to streamline the process and ensure all employees were using current publications.
- Served as primary Quality Assurance contact between the facility and external entities.

EDUCATION

Stark State College

Jan 2022 to Apr 2024

Pursuing Associate's degree